<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Social Justice &#8211; Tahsin Uddin</title>
	<atom:link href="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/category/social-justice/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://tahsinuddin.github.io</link>
	<description>Learn more about Tahsin!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 21:00:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Why Our Youth Need to Become Financially Self-Sufficient</title>
		<link>https://tahsinuddin.github.io/2022/08/11/helping-youth-become-financially-self-sufficient/</link>
					<comments>https://tahsinuddin.github.io/2022/08/11/helping-youth-become-financially-self-sufficient/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tahsin Uddin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 17:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Social Justice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://tahsinuddin.github.io/?p=636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Being financially self-sufficient generally means achieving financial independence &#8211; being able to provide for and support yourself without relying on external assistance, such as family or credit cards. For many people, this means being able to work your own jobs as needed to pay for your own bills. For others, this can go as far as to mean only consuming that which you produced yourself &#8211; such as even producing your own food! It&#8217;s a no-brainer that being in a state of financial instability can be a large stress factor for families. In fact, according to the American Psychological Association,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="is-layout-flow wp-block-group blog-post-content" style="padding-top:0px;padding-right:120px;padding-bottom:0px;padding-left:120px">
<h2 class="wp-block-gutenverse-heading guten-element guten-N6oeSU">What is Self-Sufficiency?</h2>



<p>Being financially self-sufficient generally means achieving financial independence &#8211; being able to provide for and support yourself without relying on external assistance, such as family or credit cards.</p>



<p>For many people, this means being able to work your own jobs as needed to pay for your own bills. For others, this can go as far as to mean only consuming that which you produced yourself &#8211; such as even producing your own food!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="576" src="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/breaking-a-credit-card-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-729" srcset="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/breaking-a-credit-card-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/breaking-a-credit-card-300x169.jpg 300w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/breaking-a-credit-card-768x432.jpg 768w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/breaking-a-credit-card-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/breaking-a-credit-card.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Part of becoming self-sufficient includes becoming independent from credit cards.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-gutenverse-heading guten-element guten-P7YAyu">Why is Self-Sufficiency Important?</h2>



<p>It&#8217;s a no-brainer that being in a state of financial instability can be a large stress factor for families. In fact, according to the <a href="https://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/stress" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">American Psychological Association</a>, 72% of Americans experience financial stress at least occasionally, with 22% being extremely stressed.</p>



<p>Once you become self-sufficient, you are no longer dependent on outside factors that are beyond your control. Sometimes, things will still happen &#8211; emergencies, companies going bankrupt, budget reductions. You won&#8217;t be severely affected by this though, since you know you can find a way to maintain your lifestyle.</p>



<p>Additionally, you&#8217;ll gain the freedom to own your own time to do what you want to do, without being restricted by finances.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ll also be able to make a larger impact on those in need, by making larger contributions to&nbsp;reputable charities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Self-sufficiency helps make an even larger impact at the societal level. As more people become financially self-sufficient, society at large can afford higher quality healthcare and education, and crime rates decrease as well.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1000" height="600" src="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/financial-stability-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-731" srcset="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/financial-stability-1.jpg 1000w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/financial-stability-1-300x180.jpg 300w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/financial-stability-1-768x461.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption>Becoming self-sufficient helps you reach financial stability, decreasing stress and improving society.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-gutenverse-heading guten-element guten-WBYN3E">Barriers that Prevent Self-Sufficiency?</h2>



<p>Despite how beneficial self-efficiency is for society, systemic issues in all sectors of life make it more difficult for low-income families to achieve financial stability.</p>



<p>For example, the households who use high-cost lending options &#8211; such as payday loans and check-cashing outlets &#8211; are those who can least afford it, as reported by <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.policylink.org/sites/default/files/BreakingTheCycle_0.pdf" target="_blank">Policy Link</a>. These risky alternatives in turn put low-income families at a higher risk of foreclosure and losing equity, ultimately preventing financial mobility.</p>



<p>Low-income communities are also much less likely to access quality education, are unequally targeted by the criminal justice system, and are disproportionately impacted by chronic conditions while still being less likely to afford the required treatments.</p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://www.nccp.org/demographic/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">National Center for Children in Poverty</a>, 38% of children live in low-income families nationally.</p>



<p>These and many other financial barriers continue to widen the income gap, making it more difficult for these families and youth to become self-sufficient.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/payday-loans-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-732" srcset="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/payday-loans-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/payday-loans-300x200.jpg 300w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/payday-loans-768x512.jpg 768w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/payday-loans-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/payday-loans.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Many of those who rely on high-cost lending options like payday loans are those who can least afford it.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-gutenverse-heading guten-element guten-vxiOHq">How Can We Improve Self-Sufficiency?</h2>



<p>One of the most meaningful ways we can increase the self-sufficiency of youth is by improving the financial literacy education provided in schools. We need to provide our youth with the foundational knowledge they need to make strategic and informed financial decisions.</p>



<p>This is especially important for youth as they decide how to fund their college education. </p>



<p>As <a href="https://www.champlain.edu/centers-of-experience/center-for-financial-literacy/report-national-high-school-financial-literacy/the-case-for-high-school-financial-literacy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Champlain&#8217;s National High School Financial Literacy Report</a> describes, many students need to take loans to fund their college education, but don&#8217;t completely understand factors that weigh into these decisions (such as financial aid, loans, debt, inflation, and credit scores).</p>



<p>Additionally, a significant amount of youth are working to some capacity. According to the <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/pdf/youth.pdf" target="_blank">Bureau of Labor Statistics</a>, 60.5% of all youth between ages 16-21 were working in July 2021. During the school year, the <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/pdf/coe_ssa.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">National Center for Education Statistics</a> reports that 43% of all full-time and 81% of all part-time undergraduate students were employed in 2018.</p>



<p>This makes it imperative that youth receive the proper financial literacy education to gain knowledge on concepts such as budgeting, loans, getting out of debt, savings, having multiple income streams, building your credit score, investment options, finding the right banks, etc.</p>



<p>A study by the <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/pubs/feds/2014/201468/201468pap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">FED&#8217;s Division of Research &amp; Statistics and Monetary Affairs</a> found that students who are mandated to receive financial literacy education ultimately have higher credit scores and lower delinquency rates than those in states where such education isn&#8217;t required. For example, students in Texas who received financial education 3 years after such education became mandated by law saw a 13-point credit score increase compared to those in control states.</p>



<p>Therefore, it’s clear current research supports that access to financial literacy education can make a major impact on a youth’s future financial growth.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="648" src="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/techie-youth-group-1024x648.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-733" srcset="https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/techie-youth-group-1024x648.jpg 1024w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/techie-youth-group-300x190.jpg 300w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/techie-youth-group-768x486.jpg 768w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/techie-youth-group-1536x972.jpg 1536w, https://tahsinuddin.github.io/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/techie-youth-group.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Students who graduated from Techie Youth&#8217;s Learn-to-E-Earn program.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="wp-block-gutenverse-heading guten-element guten-afHOGH">Techie Youth&#8217;s Approach</h2>



<p><a href="https://techieyouth.org/">Techie Youth</a> is a non-profit organization that strives to increase financial literacy and overall career readiness for all youth.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://techieyouth.org/enroll" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Learn to E-Learn program</a> is a completely free online series of modules that teach youth how to earn income online through entrepreneurship and other remote careers.</p>



<p>These courses range from careers such as web development to talent acquisition to even writing. They ultimately help prepare youth to enter an entry level career after graduation from the program, and to ultimately get closer to becoming self-sufficient.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would like to see this program be extended to include financial literacy as another required unit. I would also like to see different levels of certificates offered, including a smaller certificate for completing the prerequisite units to still acknowledge the skills learned by students who may not have the time to commit to the full program.</p>
</div>



<div style="height:26px" aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-spacer"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://tahsinuddin.github.io/2022/08/11/helping-youth-become-financially-self-sufficient/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
